massgeneral.org 2006-04-20

# MGH Privacy Statement

**  
Website Privacy Notice**  
At Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH), we are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the users of our site. We understand that health is a very personal, private subject, and we are committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our site. This Privacy Policy will tell you what information we collect, how it is used, and what your choices are. Please read this policy carefully. 

**1\. What personal information does MGH collect?  
** You may use most of the MGH site without providing any personal information. 

Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request. 

When providing personal information via e-mail to the hospital, please remember that e-mail messages can be viewed by other Internet users while in transit. 

If you have individualized information to communicate, please use the appropriate secure on-line form or contact the necessary party using traditional means such as phone or mail. 

You may be asked to provide personal information, such as demographic information, if you choose to complete any of the on-line forms used for event registration, special events and promotions, appointment requests, and to provide feedback. The information required to complete the transaction is noted on the form. Additional questions may be included to help us improve the services we offer. If you prefer not to enter your personal information on the web site, please call MGH at 617-726-2000.

Only authorized MGH staff who need the information you provide to perform a specific task have access to your information. All MGH hospital staff are required to attend training on Privacy and Confidentiality. 

Certain interactive patient transactions may be linked to this site as a convenience for you. If you choose to utilize a specific patient application, please be sure to read the privacy policy associated with that particular transaction. 

**2\. In what ways is the collected information used?**

MGH currently discloses personal information you provide on the Web only to process credit card information or as required by law, and has no current plans to make other disclosures of such information. We will notify you through this on-line policy if there are any changes.   
Requested information on voluntary forms is used to provide the services that you request, such as registration for classes, mailing of publications, and so forth.   
MGH may occasionally provide statistics to third parties related to the number of visitors who use the site. These statistics do not provide personally identifiable information. 

**  
3\. Does MGH use "cookies" to collect user information?  
** "Cookies" are small computer files that a web site can transfer to your computer. Examples of information we collect include how often someone visits our site and their activities while on our site. We use this information in the aggregate to understand how our visitors as a group use different resources. These reports do not contain any personally identifiable information.   
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can set your browser to refuse them or to alert you when they are being sent.

You can access the information on the MGH web site without having cookies enabled in your browser. 

**4\. Are there advertisements on MGH web site?  
** MGH does not accept advertisements on its Web Site.

**5\. How does MGH handle privacy internally?  
** MGH wants your personal information to remain as secure as possible. Accordingly, we prevent unauthorized access by a secure firewall and use of security infrastructure to protect the integrity and privacy of the personal information you provide to us. As an additional security measure, your personal information is also encrypted during transmission by Secure Socket Layer 128-bit encryption software. (Encryption is a common method used to transmit sensitive data across the Internet. Encryption temporarily makes the text unreadable during the time it is being transmitted over the Internet.) 

Please note, that for encryption to work, your browser must be Netscape or Internet Explorer version 4.0 or higher. 

**6\. Which web pages and web sites does this policy apply to?  
** This Privacy Policy applies only to the MGH Web site. The MGH site does contain links to other sites. Please be aware that this policy does not apply to sites that MGH only links to. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policies on any other sites before providing them with personal information. 

**7\. Your Consent.  
** By using the MGH Web site, you agree to acceptance of this Privacy Policy. We may occasionally need to make changes to our Privacy Policy, to reflect changes in our site and address new issues. Changes will be posted here, so please refer to this policy regularly. 

**April 2002**

* * *

**Information for Reporting Claims of Copyright Infringement**

**In accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act, 17 U.S.C. § 512 (the “DCMA”) Massachusetts General Hospital (“MGH”) and the Massachusetts General Physicians Organization ("MGPO") are registered as Service Providers with the United States Copyright Office. Notifications of copyright infringement claims occurring on MGH or MGPO's network should be reported to our designated agent, as follows:**

Robert Pappagianopoulos  
Partners Healthcare System, Inc.  
One Constitution Center, 2nd floor  
Charlestown, MA 02129

Email: [dmca-agent@partners.org](mailto:dmca-agent@partners.org)

**Any such notice must be in writing, and must include the following information as required by the DMCA:**  
· A physical or electronic signature of the copyright owner or the person authorized to act on its behalf;   
· A description of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed;   
· A description of the infringing material and information reasonably sufficient to permit MGH and MGPO to locate the material;   
· Your contact information, including your address, telephone number, and email;   
· A statement by you that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is    not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; and   
· A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and, under the pains and penalties of perjury,    that you are authorized to act on behalf of the copyright owner.
